<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Patrick Nollet</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Patrick Nollet</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 09:38:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://patrick.nollet.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slides for my AppDays 2017 talk</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2017/11/18/slides-for-my-appdays-2017-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 09:38:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2017/11/18/slides-for-my-appdays-2017-talk/</guid><description>Slides for Cross-platform: Picking the best option for your next iOS/Android app, the talk I gave at this year&amp;rsquo;s AppDays, are now available. This was a great experience. Thanks everybody for showing up! 👍</description></item><item><title>Options for cross-platform iOS/Android development in 2017</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2017/07/14/options-for-cross-platform-ios/android-development-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 08:28:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2017/07/14/options-for-cross-platform-ios/android-development-in-2017/</guid><description>Cross-platform mobile development is a topic that has been widely discussed since the first years of Android and iOS. The promise is enticing: write once, run everywhere. Don&amp;rsquo;t do the same work twice. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want that? Unfortunately, this is not as easy to achieve as it seems: you need to find the right language, the right tools, the right scope (do you want to share the UI code?) in order to be as productive as possible while taking advantage of the strengths of each platform.</description></item><item><title>Handoff</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2015/01/30/handoff/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 17:53:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2015/01/30/handoff/</guid><description>During my last week working at Applidium, I wrote a blog post to highlight a little-known feature introduced by iOS 8: Handoff. With Handoff, you can start work on one device, then switch to another nearby device and pick up where you left off. As an app developer, it is a very handy feature that helps to create a consistent cross-platform experience for your users.
You can find more details about Handoff in my article and on Apple&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>ADTransitionController - 3D transitions for your apps</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2013/07/16/adtransitioncontroller-3d-transitions-for-your-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:13:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2013/07/16/adtransitioncontroller-3d-transitions-for-your-apps/</guid><description>Romain Goyet, Pierre Felgines and I wrote ADTransitionController, a handy library that lets you easily add custom 3D transitions to any app. You can use it either with the transition APIs introduced by iOS 7 or as a full replacement for UINavigationController.
To see a demo of ADTransitionController, check out the video on its dedicated GitHub page.</description></item><item><title>Shutterbug - Image downloader for Android</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2012/09/10/shutterbug-image-downloader-for-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 18:13:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2012/09/10/shutterbug-image-downloader-for-android/</guid><description>When doing mobile development, we often find ourselves in the need of having to load a list of images, whether they are profile pictures, video thumbnails, or document previews. On iOS, SDWebImage is one of the best libraries available for that use. It handles image caching and offers great performance.
When looking for a similar library on Android, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one that fitted my needs. So I decided to port SDWebImage to Android.</description></item><item><title>ADClusterMapView - How to build a clustering framework</title><link>http://patrick.nollet.org/2012/03/13/adclustermapview-how-to-build-a-clustering-framework/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 09:49:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://patrick.nollet.org/2012/03/13/adclustermapview-how-to-build-a-clustering-framework/</guid><description>ADClusterMapView is a drop-in subclass of MKMapView that displays and animates clusters of annotations. Romain Goyet and I created it for a transportation app that needed to display thousand of stations on a map. It&amp;rsquo;s available on GitHub.
Choosing the best algorithm for the task and efficiently implementing it was an interesting process that I described on Applidium&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item></channel></rss>